<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="p0008" num="0008" sourceFile="EP 1651607B1.xml">The carboxylic acids of Formula I are believed to be the compounds that actually kill or control undesirable vegetation and are typically preferred. Analogs of these compounds in which the acid group of the picolinic acid is derivatized to form a related substituent that can be transformed within plants or the environment to a acid group possess essentially the same herbicidal effect and are within the scope of the invention. Therefore, an "agriculturally acceptable derivative", when used to describe the carboxylic acid functionality at the 2-position, is defined as any salt, ester, acylhydrazide, imidate, thioimidate, amidine, amide, orthoester, acylcyanide, acyl halide, thioester, thionoester, dithiolester, nitrile or any other acid derivative well known in the art which (a) does not substantially affect the herbicidal activity of the active ingredient, i.e., the 6-(1,1-difluoroalkyl)-4-aminopicolinic acid, and (b) is or can be hydrolyzed, oxidized or metabolized in plants or soil to the picolinic acid of Formula I that, depending upon the pH, is in the dissociated or the undissociated form. The preferred agriculturally acceptable derivatives of the carboxylic acid are agriculturally acceptable salts, esters and amides. Likewise, an "agriculturally acceptable derivative", when used to describe the amine functionality at the 4-position, is defined as any salt, silylamine, phosphorylamine, phosphinimine, phosphoramidate, sulfonamide, sulfilimine, sulfoximine, aminal, hemiaminal, amide, thioamide, carbamate, thiocarbamate, amidine, urea, imine, nitro, nitroso, azide, or any other nitrogen containing derivative well known in the art which (a) does not substantially affect the herbicidal activity of the active ingredient, i.e., the 6-(1,1-difluoroalkyl)-4-aminopicolinic acid, and (b) is or can be hydrolyzed in plants or soil to a free amine of Formula II. 
  <i>N</i>-Oxides which are also capable of breaking into the parent pyridine of Formula II are also covered by the scope of this invention.
</p>
