<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="p0137" num="0137" sourceFile="EP 2055697A1.xml">DNA was extracted from the cell line pellets and frozen tumors, tested by means of selection with specific primers, amplification with PCR, and sequencing of the different exons and introns that constitute the gene and are known to harbor mutations (MAPT: exons 9-13) or the complete gene (TUBB: exons 1-4). The following primers were designed/used to sequence the MAPT gene: exon 9, forward 5'-CTGCCTAACCCAGTGGTGA-3' and reverse 5'-CACAGTCCCACGACTCCAC-3'; exon
  <!-- EPO <DP n="51"> --> 10. forward 5'-CTCTGCCAAGTCCGAAAGTG-3' and reverse 5'- TCCTGAGAGCCCAAGAAGG-3'; exon 11, forward 5'-ATAAGGGCCTGGGCTTACAC-3' and reverse 5'-CCGCAAGTTTCACACTCAAC-3'; exon 12, forward 5'-TTCAAGTCCTGCTGCAAACC-3' and reverse 3'-CTCCAGGTGATTGAGACAGG-3'; exon 13, forward 5'-AGGCTGCAGTGAGGTGAGAT-3' and reverse 5'-CCGAGTGACAAAAGCAGGTT-3' (Invitrogen/Life Technologies). The following primers were designed/used to sequence the TUBB gene: exon 1, forward 5'-TACATGACCGGCATCGACTA-3' and reverse 5'-ACAAACTTGAGAGGGGCAAA-3'; exons 2 and 3, forward 5'-AGCGAGACTCCGTCTCAAAA-3' and reverse 5'-CTTTTGCTGTGTCCTTGCAC-3'; exon 4a, forward 5'-CGAGGGAATTATTTGAAAAGTTG-3' and reverse 5'-GGCATCGAAGACCTGCTG-3'; exon 4b, forward 5'-TTCTTTATGCCTGGCTTTGC-3' and reverse 3'-CCCAGAATGGCAGAAACCTA-3'; exon 4c, forward 5'-TCCCTCAGAATTTGTGTTTGC-3' and reverse 5'-GCTCGAGTGAGGGAGGTAGA-3V; exon 4d, forward 5'-TGTCAGCAGTATTATCTCCACTTT-3' and reverse 5'-TTAAGTGTCAATTTAAGGAGA-3' (Invitrogen/Life Technologies). The 25-µL PCR reaction consisted of 0.2 µmol/L concentration of each outside primer along with 150 ng of genomic DNA, HotMaster Mix 2.5x (Eppendorf) containing 960 µmol/L deoxynucleotide triphosphates, 54 mmol/L KCl, 3.0 mmol/L MgCl2, and 0.6 units of Taq Polymerase. Thermocycler conditions were initial cycle at 95°C for 3 min, followed by 10 cycles 94jC for 45 s, 57.6jC for 1 min, and 72°C for 1 min; 20 cycles of 89°C for I min, 57.6°C for 1 min, and 72°C for 1 min. PCR product clean-up consisted of 3 µL Shrimp Alkaline Phosphatase and 0.3 AL Exonuclease1 (GE Healthcare) per sample incubated at 37°C for 1 h followed by one step of 80°C for 15 min. The existence of a variant was determined by direct nucleotide sequencing. Sequencing was done using an ABI 3730XL Sequencer (Applied Biosystems), following standard dideoxy terminator protocols. Sequences were analyzed using Sequencher (Genecodes). Only changes present in both strands were identified as single nucleotide polymorphisms.
</p>
